dickblick.com 2019-05-11

# Security and Privacy - BLICK art materials

Last Updated: November 29, 2018

This Privacy Policy describes the information collected through this website and the online services we provide (together, the “ **Services** ”) and how that information is used and shared. Blick Art Materials, LLC (collectively with its affiliates, “ **Blick** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ,” or “ **our** ”) and its suppliers may collect, use, and share the types of information described below in connection with your access to and use of the Services (together, “ **Collected Information** ”). 

**By accessing or using the Services, you agree on behalf of yourself and any organization or company that you represent (together, “you”) that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and that you consent to the collection, use, and sharing of information as discussed below. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, do not access or use the Services.**

**This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of ourTerms of Use. Blick reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting to the Services and, by accessing or using the Services after changes are posted, you agree to those changes. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Services or otherwise communicated to you. Please refer to this page to review our most current policies and terms of use.**

  * Information Security
  * What information is collected?
  * How is information used and disclosed?
  * What if I don't want email or catalogs?
  * Affiliate Program Ecommerce Disclosure
  * Third-Party Websites
  * Access by Children
  * Access from Outside the United States
  * How to Access Your Personal Information
  * Contact Us
  * Your California Privacy Rights

## Information Security

Blick does not guarantee that loss, misuse, or alteration of Collected Information will not occur, but we have security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control. The Services’ checkout process is protected with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), the standard for encrypted commercial transactions throughout the Internet. 

Blick uses GoDaddy, the industry leader, as its security verification service. Transaction information is encrypted prior to transmission. In addition, our site ownership, operation, and identity is verified as authentic and valid. Click on the GoDaddy Secured icon at the bottom of every page to verify and view Blick’s security certificate. 

All web pages pass encrypted information. When you request one of these pages, the page's URL begins with https instead of http, and the "security" icon on your browser has the appearance of a closed padlock. 

The storage and communication of information can never be completely secure, so we do not guarantee that communications or other information that you submit or that are otherwise provided to us will be completely secure. If you become aware of any breach of Services security or this Privacy Policy, please notify us immediately using the contact information below. If our security system is breached, we will notify you of the breach only if and to the extent required under applicable law. 

Return to Top

## What information is collected?

**Personal Information.** You can visit and use the Services without sharing personal information, but you will be required to provide personal information when you register for an account on the Services, order products through the Services, fill out certain online forms, or use certain other features of the Services. We will collect any personal information from or about you that you choose to submit to us, which may include your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, payment information, and the month and day of your birth. Specifically, we collect your personal information when you register for an online Blick account, when you request a Blick catalog, when you purchase products using the Services, in receiving and fulfilling information requests, when you submit a career inquiry or upload a resume, and when you respond to communications from us (e.g., surveys and promotional offers). If you provide your mobile or other telephone number to us, you consent to receiving telephone calls from us at that telephone number as described below. We will use your personal information as described below, including to process your orders and to provide you with information and communications that you request or that we believe are relevant or may be of interest to you, subject to applicable laws and the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**Account Information.** To register for an online Blick account, you will need to submit your name, billing address, phone number, and email address. You may also provide your school, organization or company name. 

**Payment Information.** Purchases of products or services must be made by credit or debit card, by using PayPal, by using Amazon Payments, gift cards, or check or money order. All credit and debit card information is provided directly to our PCI-compliant third-party payment processor. Blick does not directly access, handle, or store your credit or debit card information. To make a purchase through the Services you will need to submit your name and your credit or debit card number, expiration date, security code, and billing address. Payment by credit or debit card is subject to the approval of the card issuer. We will not be liable in any way if a card issuer refuses to accept a credit or debit card for any reason. If you make a purchase using PayPal, you may need to log in to your PayPal account. PayPal may use Collected Information as described in its [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). If you make a purchase using Amazon Payments, you may need to log in to your Amazon account. Amazon may use Collected Information as described in the [Amazon Payments Privacy Notice](https://pay.amazon.com/us/help/201751600). We will maintain a record of the purchases that you make using the Services. 

**Credit Applications for Institutional Accounts.** If you are a company, organization or a school, you may be eligible to purchase products via the Services “on account” as described here. To request an institutional account you will be required to submit a credit application and additional terms may apply. 

**Mailing List Information.** If you sign up or otherwise opt in to receive promotions from us, you will need to submit your name and email address. You may also provide your physical address, telephone number, and, if applicable, the name of your school or company. We will use this information to provide you with promotional and other electronic and hard copy communications. You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from us at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in the applicable email or by following the instructions below (see What if I don’t want email or catalogs?). We may use third-party email providers to deliver these communications to you. 

**User-Generated Material.** You are responsible for any comments, data, images, text, photos, artwork, audio, videos, and other content and material that you create, post, upload, transmit, display, publish, distribute, broadcast, or otherwise submit using the Services (together, “ **User-Generated Material** ”). User-Generated Material that you submit is posted on the Services at your own risk. With regard to User-Generated Material consisting of Blick product reviews, if you elect to include your name, we may excerpt those reviews in Blick advertising and marketing materials and may include your name with any such excerpts. We cannot guarantee that submitted User-Generated Material will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. You understand that, even after removal, copies of User-Generated Material you have submitted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages and may have been copied or stored by other users of the Services. For information on submitting User-Generated Material, please review our Terms of Use.

**Career Opportunities.** To submit a job application for openings at our retail locations, you will be redirected to our online career portal, which is provided by iCIMS, and you will be required to either create an iCIMS account (if you do not already have one) or to log in using your Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+, or Microsoft account as described below under “Single Sign-On.” Job applications submitted through that career portal, including your resume and all other materials and information you provide in the course of submitting job applications, will be submitted directly to iCIMS and will then be shared with Blick. We encourage you to review [iCIMS’s Privacy Policy.](https://www.icims.com/legal/privacy-policy/)

To submit a job application for openings at our home office, you will be redirected to LinkedIn and you will be required to create a LinkedIn account (if you do not already have one). Job applications submitted through that career portal, including your resume and all other materials and information you provide in the course of submitting job applications, will be submitted directly to LinkedIn and will then be shared with Blick. We encourage you to review [LinkedIn’s Privacy Policy.](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

We will use your job application to evaluate your qualifications and to otherwise consider or respond to your application for employment. Your submission of a job application does not in any way require Blick to review that application or consider you for employment. 

**Lists and Other Account Activity.** If you use the Services while signed into your Blick account, we will collect information on how you use your account and the Services, for example, the items and information that you add to your Blick wish lists. We will also collect any information you provide to create BlickU course supply lists, including the name of the school, the name and email address of the instructor, and course-related information. You can publish your BlickU lists for public viewing by selecting that option in your account. If you choose to email a BlickU list to students or other persons, you will be required to input those email addresses. We will use those email addresses to send a one-time email containing the message you’ve provided linking to the BlickU course supply list. 

**Affiliate Program Sign-Up.** If you choose to sign up for our Affiliate Program you will be redirected to a third-party website and will be required to enter your name and email address. We encourage you to review that third party’s privacy policy. 

**IP Addresses and Related Data.** As you browse, order products via, and otherwise use the Services, the servers used to operate and provide the Services may collect data pertaining to you and the equipment, software, and communication methods you use to access the Internet and the Services, including Internet protocol (“ **IP** ”) addresses assigned to the computer from where you access the Internet, your Internet service provider (ISP), your device ID number, your approximate geographic location, your browser type, the pages you access on the Services, the websites you access before and after visiting the Services, your activity and your path through the pages of the Services, the length of time you spend on the Services, date and time stamps, and clickstream data. Blick does not use this information to identify or contact individual users. We use this data to administer the Services and its servers, to generate statistical information, to monitor and analyze Services traffic and usage patterns, to monitor and prevent fraud, to investigate complaints and violations of our policies, and to improve the Services’ content and the products, services, and materials, and other content that we describe or make available through the Services. We may combine this information with personal information, other Collected Information, and information obtained from third parties for the purposes discussed below. 

**What are cookies, and do you use them?** The Services automatically use cookies to improve your shopping experience and otherwise to facilitate and enhance the user experience on the Services. Cookies are bits of information your web browser stores on your computer’s hard drive. The Services may use both cookies that we implement and cookies implemented by our suppliers and other third parties. We use cookies to track how you access and use the Services, to learn when and how users visit the Services, to learn how popular Services pages are and aren’t, to learn which search terms are used to find the Services, and to learn which websites direct you to the Services. We also use cookies to help display certain information on the Services and to improve your enjoyment of the Services, for example, by remembering your contact and other information when you access or use the Services. For example, when you visit the Services, a cookie helps us keep track of your order as you shop, and if you have registered for an online customer account, a cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to the Services and provides you with access to your account information as well as helps assist in reducing data input during checkout. 

Blick also uses various third-party cookies to sponsor other websites you may visit, provide promotions on other websites, and capture visitor website usage in aggregate (not individually) for analytic and diagnostic purposes. Our Services suppliers may use cookies and other tracking technologies, such as pixel tags, to track Services visitors across the Internet to understand how you get to the Services. 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can disable this function, however, disabling cookies may impact your use and enjoyment of the Services. For example, if cookies are disabled, you will not be able to add items to your online shopping cart. 

Due to the automatic collection of data using cookies, we do not honor “do not track” requests. 

If you are concerned about cookies and want to avoid keeping them on your machine, we urge you to use or purchase one of the many “Cookie Eliminator” programs readily available. Alternatively, many modern web browsers allow you to configure your preferred “Privacy” settings as they relate to cookies. For example, you may choose to not accept “3rd party cookies” or you may wish to “delete” all cookies upon closing/exiting the browser application. 

**Location Information.** In addition to the approximate geographic location information collected as discussed above, we may, with your consent, access more specific location information in order to enhance the user experience and increase the usefulness of the Services. This includes both geographical location information that you input using the Services (e.g., using our Find a Store feature) and geographical location information collected by device-based location services (including GPS data). You may choose to allow us to access your location by granting the Services access to your location when prompted or through your device’s location services settings. 

**Analytics.** The Services use third-party analytics tools (e.g., Google Analytics, Hotjar, and New Relic) to collect and process data about your use of the Services, including when you visit the Services, URLs of the websites that you visit prior to visiting the Services and when you visit those websites, and IP addresses assigned to the devices from where you access the Internet. Our analytics providers may set and read cookies to collect this data and your web browser will automatically send data collected by those cookies to our analytics providers. Our analytics providers use this data to provide us with reports that we will use to improve the Services’ structure and content. For more information on how Google uses this data, visit [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and Google’s page on [How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). To prevent this data from being used by Google Analytics, follow the instructions to download and install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) for each web browser you use. Using the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on will not prevent Company from using other analytics tools and will not prevent data from being sent to the Services itself or to Google. You may opt out to Hotjar’s creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of the Services, and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by opting out [here](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out). You may disable cookies as discussed above, but that may impact your use and enjoyment of the Services. 

**Google Analytics’ Advertising Features.** Additionally, we have enabled and implemented the following Google Analytics Advertising Features: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Demographics and Interest Reporting, Segments, DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration, and DoubleClick Bid Manager Integration. Remarketing with Analytics uses Google Analytics cookies to serve advertisements to you across the Internet based on your visits to the Services. Demographics and Interest Reporting uses a third-party cookie to collect information about our Services traffic by tracking users across websites and across time, which generates a report for us to better understand our Services users. Segments allows us to isolate and analyze subsets of Services users by sorting our Google Analytics data. DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration and DoubleClick Bid Manager Integration allow us to view, analyze, and create remarketing lists using our DoubleClick Campaign data. To opt out of remarketing advertising provided through Google, to customize your ad preferences, or to limit Google’s collection or use this information, visit [Google’s Safety Center](https://safety.google/) and [Google’s Ad Settings](https://myaccount.google.com/not-supported?pli=1) and follow [Google’s personalized ad opt-out instructions](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en&ref_topic=7048998). Opting out will not affect your use of the Services. 

**Google AdWords.** We also use Google AdWords, an online advertising service provided by Google, to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on the Services. Google uses your Internet searches, cookies, and similar identifiers (e.g., pixel tags) to collect anonymous information about your visits to the Services and your interaction with our products and services to generate targeted advertisements to you on other websites that you visit across the Internet. To opt out of remarketing advertising provided through Google, to customize your ad preferences, or to limit Google’s collection or use this information, visit [Google’s Safety Center](https://safety.google/) and [Google’s Ad Settings](https://myaccount.google.com/not-supported?pli=1) and follow [Google’s personalized ad opt-out instructions](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en&ref_topic=7048998). Opting out will not affect your use of the Services. 

**Advertising Networks, Personalized Advertising, Remarketing, and Retargeting.** From time to time the Services may use or participate in advertising networks and related advertising services that are managed and provided by third-party advertising servers, advertising agencies, technology vendors, and research firms. These services collect anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with the Services and other websites and will use that information to target advertisements for goods and services. The information collected may be associated with your personal information. These targeted advertisements may appear on the Services or on other websites. Advertising networks often gather data about consumers who view advertisements to make inferences about a consumer’s interests and preferences, which enables their computers to deliver advertisements directly targeted to the consumer’s specific interests. This practice is often referred to as “online behavioral advertising.” For example, a third-party advertising network might collect the type of Internet browser you use, the type of computer operating system you use, the domain name of a website you visit, whether or not you visit specific pages of the Services and other websites, the location of your Internet service provider, the date and time of a visit to a website, and other interactions between you and a website. 

**To change your preferences with respect to certain online ads and to obtain more information about third-party ad networks and online behavioral advertising, please visit the[National Advertising Initiative Consumer opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Program.](http://www.aboutads.info/)** Please remember that changing your settings with individual browsers or ad networks will not necessarily carry over to other browsers or ad networks. As a result, depending on the opt-outs you request, you may still see our ads from time to time. 

**Single Sign-On (Career Portal Only).** If applicable to you, you may log into the Blick career portal provided by iCIMS (as discussed above) using your Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+, or Microsoft account by providing your log-in information for those third-party services when prompted. If you choose to use this single sign-on feature, iCIMS may access, handle, and store any content and other information that you have provided through Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+, or Microsoft (as applicable). These single sign-on features may require us to implement cookies, plug-ins, and application protocol interfaces (APIs) provided by those third parties to facilitate those communications and features. We do not and cannot control any policies or terms of any third party, including Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+, and Microsoft. All information you have provided to Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+, or Microsoft is subject to the applicable privacy policy: see [Facebook’s Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php), [LinkedIn’s Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy); and [Microsoft’s Privacy Statement.](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement)

Return to Top

## How is information used and disclosed?

In addition to the uses described above, Blick and its suppliers may use and share Collected Information as described below. We will not sell, rent, or share Collected Information except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy or as permitted by applicable law. 

**Purpose Collected.** We will use your personal information for the purpose for which it was collected, for example, to process and communicate with you in connection with your purchases and account and to provide you with information and communications that you request. Your location information will be used to identify Blick locations near you and to understand where our users are located. If you provide us with your telephone number in connection with your account, we may call you at that telephone number regarding your purchases and account. We will make User-Generated Material available to other users of the Services as applicable. For example, if you submit materials while entering an online Blick contest or if you submit product reviews, other users of the Services will be able to view, copy, and use that content. If you contact us for support or assistance in using the Services, we may use Collected Information to determine whether or not your system meets the minimum requirements needed to access and use the Services and otherwise to contact you regarding your request. 

**Communication with You.** We may use Collected Information to notify you of changes made to the Services (for example, changes to our Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy), market products and services to you, and to send you promotional materials and other communications as described above. Blick maintains a list of current and potential customers. If you order from us, or if you request a catalog, then we will send you a new catalog from time to time, depending on the amount of business you do with us. 

**Sharing Collected Information with Our Suppliers.** We may share Collected Information with our Services management and hosting suppliers, payment processors, marketing and public relations service providers, email service suppliers, and other suppliers as necessary for us to provide the Services and our products and services to you and as may otherwise be permitted by applicable law. Our suppliers are authorized to and may use and disclose Collected Information as necessary for them to provide the applicable services to us. 

**Sharing Collected Information with Other Third Parties.** Like other companies in our industry, we may rent, exchange, or otherwise share names and mailing addresses with companies offering products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive catalogs or solicitations from those third parties, please call us at 1-800-828-4548, email us at [circulation@dickblick.com](mailto:circulation@dickblick.com), or write us at Blick Art Materials, P.O. Box 1267, Galesburg, IL 61402-1267. Please include the phrase “California Privacy Request” in the subject line of any email request. Please also identify the domain name of the website you are inquiring about and include your name, email address, and mailing address in any request. Additionally, you may opt out of receiving communications from any such third party pursuant to such third party’s policies. We do not control any third parties or their policies. 

**Aggregate Data.** We may aggregate personal information and other Collected Information to create anonymous aggregate data on Services users, which describes users as a group but does not reveal the identity of individual users. We may use aggregate data to understand users’ needs, to determine user demographics and usage patterns, to determine what kinds of products and services we can provide, and to improve and enrich our products and services and the Services. 

**Evaluation and Improvement of the Services.** We may use Collected Information: to analyze, develop, and improve the content, materials, products, and services that we make available through the Services and the Services’ functionality; to inform marketing and communication plans and strategies; to evaluate user needs and customize Services content, promotional emails, and your browsing experience; and for other legitimate and lawful business purposes. 

**Security and Protection of Rights.** We may use Collected Information and share it with third parties to the extent permitted by applicable law, including in the event of a subpoena, court order, or law enforcement request. Blick will use Collected Information and share it with third parties if we believe doing so is necessary to operate the Services or to protect our rights or the rights of others, including disclosing information necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action in the event of a violation of our contracts, terms, or policies. 

**Business Transactions.** All Collected Information is exclusively the property of Blick but, in the event Blick or substantially all of its assets are acquired or merged with another company, or upon a change in control or reorganization, all Collected Information may be transferred or sold to the successor company. That successor will be bound by this Privacy Policy as it applies to that information. 

Return to Top

## What if I don't want email or catalogs?

If you have an online Blick account, you have the option to change certain privacy settings once you have logged into your account on the Services. Once logged in, click on "My Account" (located on every page of our site, in the upper right corner). 

Click the “Account Preferences” option to manage your catalog subscriptions and how we share your mailing address. On this page, you will find a series of checkboxes. Use these checkboxes to tell us whether you are interested in receiving mailings from us and/or mailings from other companies that may be interested in contacting you. To finalize changes to your mailing preferences, click the green UPDATE button. 

Click “Email Preferences” to access and edit your Blick email subscription status. These changes will be finalized as soon as you click the submit button. 

If you do not have an online Blick account, but you are already a customer of ours, please feel free to write us using the contact information below or email us at [circulation@dickblick.com](mailto:circulation@dickblick.com) to let us know your mail and email preferences. 

It helps to include your customer number (available on any recent invoice or on the address label of a recent catalog) so that we can match your request with information in our records. If you are interested in avoiding catalog mailings in general, please contact the Direct Marketing Association and the United States Postal Service, which maintain a list of consumers who do not want to receive unsolicited catalogs. 

If you have asked us not to send catalogs, but you still receive one, you may be on other mailing lists or have a duplicate account. Although we try to avoid it, duplicate records for a customer do occasionally occur. We really appreciate your help in avoiding unwanted mailings. 

To notify us of any changes in your mail or email preferences or duplications, please contact us at [circulation@dickblick.com](mailto:circulation@dickblick.com), call us at 1-800-828-4548, or send us an ordinary letter at:   
Blick Art Materials   
P.O. Box 1267   
Galesburg, IL 61402-1267 

Return to Top

## Affiliate Program Ecommerce Disclosure

In accordance with industry practices, third parties that link to our Services on their websites may be compensated for sales originating from those websites. Click here to learn more about our Affiliate Program. 

Return to Top

## Third-Party Websites

The Services may link to, or be linked to, websites not maintained or controlled by Blick. Blick is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third parties or any third-party websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party websites or to any personal or other information that you may provide to third parties. You should read the privacy policy for each website that you visit. 

Return to Top

## Access by Children

The Services are not directed at children under 13 years of age. Blick does not knowingly collect or use information from children under 13 through the Services. 

Return to Top

## Access from Outside the United States

If you are visiting the Services from outside the United States, please be aware that Collected Information may be transferred to, stored in, and processed in the United States (where our and our suppliers’ servers and databases are located and operated). The data protection and related laws and regulations of the United States might not be as comprehensive as those in the country from which you are accessing the Services. 

Return to Top

## How to Access Your Personal Information

To access or update your personal information as it exists in our records, please visit the online Blick account you have created for yourself, if applicable, or contact us using the contact information below. 

Return to Top

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, contact us by email at [info@dickblick.com](mailto:info@dickblick.com), by telephone at (800) 828-4548, or by mail at Blick Art Materials, P.O. Box 1267, Galesburg, IL 61402-1267. 

Return to Top
